Personal
Marist College
Personal
1789 1984
Marist Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road, Poughkeepsie, New York 12601
Lowell Thomas
2.1.1.2.1.4
1203 Linear feet
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
Glass Plate Negatives
- Lowell Thomas Papers
  - Graphic Material, 2
    - Photographs, 2.1
      - Glass Plate Negatives, 2.1.1
        - Lowell Thomas, 2.1.1.2
          - Indexed Photographs, 2.1.1.2.1
            - Personal, 2.1.1.2.1.4
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The author, With Lawrence in Arabia], 1918; 49 (Box 1270)
                5x7
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The author, With Lawrence in Arabia], 1918; 50
                4x5
                film
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in front of tent, Arabia [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Lawrence and the author], 1918; 51
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in front of tent, Arabia [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Lawrence and the author], 1918; 52
                - Lowell Thomas and T. E. Lawrence standing in front of tent, 1918; 53
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in London in Arab clothes, circa 1919; 54
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas, three quarter view, bushes, full-faced, in Arab clothes, circa 1919; 55
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas, three quarter side view, serious, in Arab clothes, circa 1919; 56
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in London in Arab clothes, circa 1919; 57
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, full-faced, with sickly smiles, circa 1919; 58
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, side view, laughing, circa 1919; 59
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, close-up, standing, circa 1919; 60
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, squatting, London, close-up, circa 1919; 61
                - Lowell Thomas, wearing Arab headdress, on Emir Feisal’s horse, 1918; 62
                - Lowell Thomas on Emir Feisal’s Arabian horse, 1918; 63
                - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting at entrance to tent, 1918; 64
                - Profile view of Lowell Thomas and General Edmund Allenby, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Allenby and author], 1918; 65
                - Profile view of Lowell Thomas and General Edmund Allenby [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Allenby and author], 1918; 66
                4x7
                - Lowell Thomas with motion picture camera in airplane before taking off for a flight from Egypt to Jerusalem [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lowell Thomas in an open cockpit Breguet about to take off with Major A. J. Evans to follow the route of the Israelites across the Sinai Desert], 1918; 67
                - Lowell Thomas with Mayor of Gaza having a quiet smoke, the Mayor’s nephews at right, 1918; 68
                - Lowell Thomas with Mayor of Gaza having a quiet smoke, the Mayor’s nephews at right, 1918; 69
                - Lowell Thomas taking notes alongside a disabled tank near Gaza, 1918; 70
                - Harry Chase and two men examine a tank, 1918; 71
                - Lowell Thomas in armored car, 1000 feet below sea level, 1918; 72
                3.5x4.5
                - Lowell Thomas in pith helmet sits and an Arab man stands in front of tent with cameras and other equipment on the ground, 1918; 73
                - Leaning Tower of Pisa, Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, and Major Piero Tozzi in foreground, 1917; 74
                - Leaning Tower of Pisa, Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, and Major Piero Tozzi in foreground, 1917; 75
                - [left to right] Major Piero Tozzi, Lowell Thomas and Colonel Webb Hayes sit in gondola; gondolier stands at rear, 1917; 76
                - [seated left to right in rear of automobile] Lowell Thomas, Colonel Webb Hayes and Major Piero Tozzi; soldiers on horseback in background, 1917; 77
                - Luisa Tetrazzini, Major Piero Tozzi, and Lowell Thomas stand in front of Luisa’s limousine, 1917; 78
                - Lowell Thomas and Major Piero Tozzi seated at table while drinking coffee, Venice, 1917; 79
                - General Giuseppe “Peppino” Garibaldi and dog, Lowell Thomas looking at camera, 1917; 1 (Box 1271)
                - General Giuseppe “Peppino” Garibaldi and dog, Lowell Thomas not looking at camera, 1917; 2
                - Lowell Thomas and Major Barracca and others, airplane in background, 1917; 3
                - Lowell Thomas and unidentified man with arm in sling, in Padova, 1917; 4
                - Lowell Thomas on dogsled in Alps, many people in the background, 1917; 5
                - Lowell Thomas squatting beside two children in France, 1917; 6
                - Lowell Thomas in Malta with unidentified Admiral, 1918; 7
                - Lowell Thomas wearing helmet and goggles seated in cockpit of airplane, 1918; 8
                - Lowell Thomas and Italian officer standing before a statue of General von Hindenburg, 1918; 9
                - Harry Chase in Arab clothes, three quarter view, London, circa 1919; 10
                - Harry Chase in Arab clothes, squatting, London, circa 1919; 11
                - Dale Carnegie [also known as Dale Carnagey], pith helmet, side view, seated, hands clasped, circa 1919; 12
                - Dale Carnegie [also known as Dale Carnagey], bust, pith helmet, full-faced view, 1918; 13
                - Dale Carnegie [also known as Dale Carnagey], bust, side view, pith helmet, 1918; 14
                - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas in cart holding umbrella, 1918; 15
                - Veiled woman of Arabia [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Types of city headdress for women], 1918; 16
                - Veiled woman, full length, aboard ship [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Types of city headdress for women], 1918; 17
                - Arab woman, Dorothy Waldegrave as Miss America, Major Peter Drummond, Lieutenant McCall McCowan, 1918; 18
                - Veiled woman, Dorothy Waldegrave as Miss America, Major Peter Drummond, Lieutenant McCall McCowan, more serious, 1918; 19
                - Dorothy Waldegrave as Miss America, serious, 1918; 20
                - Dorothy Waldegrave as Miss America, smiling, 1918; 21
                - Lowell Thomas with Arab clothes, bust, by Monte Luke, 1918; 22
                - Lowell Thomas and three soldiers, 1918; 23
                - Portrait of Lowell Thomas in military uniform, 1918; 24
                - Lowell Thomas, wearing cap, operates a motion picture camera on a mountain, several soldiers nearby, 1918; 25
                - Lowell Thomas, wearing cap, operates a motion picture camera on a mountain, several soldiers nearby, 1918; 26
                - Lowell Thomas and two French children, close-up, 1918; 27
                - Lowell Thomas reading the “Balkan News,” Red Cross, 1918; 28
                - Sketch of Lowell Thomas by James McBey [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The author sketched by James McBey, official artist for Allenby’s forces in the Holy Land], 1918; 29
                - Lowell Thomas and man wielding a rifle on Mount Hor, 1918; 30
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, full-faced [broken, see next envelope for remaining pieces], 1918; 31
                - Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress and clothes, full length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lowell Thomas in Arab costume when he was with Lawrence of Arabia], 1918; 32
                - Lowell Thomas and Essad Pasha, Albanian dictator, 1918; 33
                - Lowell Thomas and men in front of elaborate building, 1918; 34
                2.25x3.5
                - Soldiers talking in front of Hindenburg statue, Berlin, Germany, 1918; 35
                - Unidentified man, 1918; 36
                - Unidentified man with two horses, 1918; 37
                - Unidentified man in front of barn [?], 1918; 38
                - Unidentified man playing baseball, 1918; 39
                - Two camels mating, two men standing next to them, 1918; 40
                - Two camels mating, two men standing next to them, 1918; 41
                4.5x6.5
                - Two camels mating, man standing next to them, 1918; 42
                - Two camels mating, man standing next to them, 1918; 43
                - Lowell Thomas with unidentified man holding cane, 1918; 44
                - Lowell Thomas talking with two men, 1918; 45
                - Lowell Thomas with two men and a motion picture camera, 1918; 46
                - Lowell Thomas with cane, talking to soldier, 1918; 47
                - Soldier showing two children a gun, Lowell Thomas pointing at left, 1918; 48
                - Men on ship, Lowell Thomas [?] with back to camera, 1918; 49
                - Lowell Thomas passport, Germany, 1/9/1919; 50
                - Lowell Thomas passport, Germany, 12/17/1918; 51
                - Lowell Thomas passport, Switzerland, 12/6/1918; 52
                - Lowell Thomas passport, Germany, 1/1/1919; 53
                - Lowell Thomas passport, Sudan, 1918; 54
                - Three German helmets, 1918; 55
                - Kaiser’s helmet, 1918; 56
                - Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas wearing Kaiser’s helmet, 1918; 57
                - Lowell Thomas standing on stairs next to arch, undated; 58
                3.5x4.75
                - Ancestor of Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas or Lowell Thomas, undated; 59
                - Lowell Thomas with two men, undated; 60